Immediately after this video,
本视频结束后
you're going to see something that looks like this.
你会看到一个这样的工具
And this is called a Jupyter Notebook.
它叫做 Jupyter Notebook
It is a great tool for writing and documenting Python code.
它是一个编写和记录 Python 代码的好工具
So, as you can see, this notebook is made of cells.
你可以看到 它是由单元格组成的
And I've got a cell highlighted now,
这里有一个高亮的单元格
and I can use my arrow keys to navigate up and down to the cells.
我可以使用方向键在单元格间上下移动
And this cell, as you can see here,
从这里可以看到
is a markdown cell.
这是一个 Markdown 单元格
And I don't want to talk too much about this except to say that markdown
这里我们不会详细讨论 Markdown 你只需知道
is a sort of fancy way to make text look a little nicer.
它是一种让文本看起来更漂亮的标记语言
So, sometimes you'll see
因此 有时候你可以看到
these cells in this format and this can be a little bit annoying.
这些单元格是这种格式的 这会有点麻烦
And if you don't know what to do, it can be a big problem.
如果你不知道该怎么做 那就是大麻烦了
Basically, this format is showing you the editing mode.
简单点说 这种格式显示的是编辑模式
So here, you can see the syntax for making something a header.
在这里 这个句式可以把内容变为标题
And here, you can see the syntax for making something bold.
在这里 这个句式可以把内容变为粗体
If you ever wind up in this mode and you want to get back to the nicer looking mode.
在这种模式下 你可能想要切换为更美观的界面
So just like control and enter,
在 Markdown 单元格中 我们可以
works in markdown cells.
使用 Ctrl 和回车键操作
We can also look at a code cell.
同样 我们还可以使用 Code 单元格
And here, we have a python comment followed by a print statement.
在这里 我们有一个 Python 注释 后面是一个输出语句
And I can do control and enter here.
我们可以在这里按 Ctrl + 回车
And sure enough, it printed, "Hello World!"
然后它就会输出 "Hello World!"
Now, there's actually another way you can run a cell and
还有另一种方式可以运行一个单元格
that's by pressing shift and enter.
即按下 Shift + 回车
And that does the same thing except it advances your cursor down to the cell below.
它的功能是一样的 不同的是 它会把光标移到下面的单元格中
That's actually really nice.
这实际上挺不错的
So, when you see a notebook like this one and you start at the top,
例如 你有一个这样的 notebook
you can just kind of advance through by pressing shift enter,
你可以并从顶端开始时一路按 Shift + 回车
shift enter, shift enter.
Shift + 回车 Shift + 回车
And I'm going to let you play with this more on your own.
你可以自己继续操作
But there are two important things I do want to say first.
但首先 有两件事情要强调一下
Number one: this is your workspace.
第一 这是你的工作区
You can do whatever you want in these notebooks.
你可以在这些 notebook 中做任何操作
You will not cause any lasting damage.
不会造成任何不可逆的损失
There's nothing to break.
一切都非常安全
So, for example, I could go here and let's say,
例如 我可以在这里
I want to delete every single cell for some reason.
出于某种原因 删掉一个单元格
I'm going to press the D key twice to delete the cell.
我会按 D 键两次删除单元格
And I'm going to do that on every single one. All right.
我会删掉所有单元格 好了
So, all my cells are gone.
现在 所有单元格都消失了
I could even save it.
我还可以保存操作结果
Now, you may think we've caused
现在 你可能觉得
lasting damage and we'll never be able to return to this exercise.
内容已经彻底丢失 我们没法再继续下面的练习了
But that is not true.
不要担心
Down here in the bottom, we select Menu and then go to reset data.
在底部这里 我们选择 MENU 然后选择 RESET DATA
And it looks ominous, but it's okay.
出现了一个警告 似乎不太妙 别担心
We just type in Reset data to confirm.
我们需要输入 "Reset data" 来确认
The reason it's so hard to delete is because,
删除内容之所以这么困难
you know, this is your workspace.
是因为这是你的工作空间
You may have a lot of work on here that you don't want to delete.
里面可能有很多工作成果 你不想删除
So, we just want to be sure that you don't do anything you don't want to do.
因此 我们需要确保你不会一时糊涂 把内容改得面目全非
But sure enough, after we reset data, we're back to where we started.
当然了 数据重置后 我们又得从头开始
So, that's the first thing I wanted to say.
因此 我要强调的第一件事就是
You cannot cause lasting damage.
这里的数据足够安全
And the second I want to say is that,
第二 我想说的是
again, this is really your workspace.
这是真正属于你的工作区
You can even create new files. You can do whatever you want.
你可以创建新文件 你可以做任何操作
So, I'm going to create a new notebook in Python 3.
因此 我准备在 Python 3 中创建一个新 notebook
Maybe I'll call it math_practice.
我将其命名为 math_practice
And I can play around Python code.
我还可以编写 Python 代码
Let's try two plus two.
我们试一下 2 + 2
Sure enough, it's equal to four.
当然 结果是 4
And I can browse all of my files by clicking on this Jupyter logo.
我还可以点击这里的 Jupyter 标志浏览我的所有文件
Oh, it's prompting me to stay because I haven't saved my changes. That's good.
噢 跳出了一个提示 因为我没有保存更改 不错
Let me go through that process of saving the changes.
接下来我来保存更改
And I can click on the Jupyter logo again.
然后再次点击上面的 Jupyter 标志
And now, I can see all of my files,
现在 我可以看到所有文件
math_practice and playground are both here.
math_practice 和 playground 都显示在这里
So I can click on playground and I'm back here.
我可以点击 playground 然后又返回这里了
All right. I just wanted to show you those few things.
好的 上面只是演示一下
You'll learn more as you play around in this programming playground and you'll
你可以在 playground 文件中练习并熟悉相关操作
learn more about how to use this tool throughout the end of the degree. Have fun.
随着课程的进展 你会越来越了解这个工具 好好享受吧